Hello, my name is Katarzyna, and I'm going to guide you through the course material
of this statistical Programming Languages course. As you can see, at the bottom of this video, they are automatically generated captions.
And I hope they will be useful for you. So today, we are going just to go through the download and the installation of R and RStudio.
Let us jump straight to it. So let us open a browser of our choice, and let us type RDownload.
One of the first few options you should see is
the R project for Statistical Computing, this is www.r-project.org website. Let us click on this link.
So here, you can see that there are many links up.
But we need to download R first, so let us click on the link directing us to the downloading page, so Download R.
And then once again, here you can see many links.
So basically here, you are just asked to select a server location from which you are going to download R.
So, since we are in Germany, let us scroll down and select one of the German servers, so I'm going to select the one in Gottingen.
Alright, and then here we have 3 options for the download and the installation of R.
We have a download for Linux, Mac, and Windows. Since I'm now currently on the Windows machine, I'm going to click Download R for Windows.
But, as you will see, I shared with you a link to a YouTube video with a step-by-step installation for Mac.
So let me just jump to the installation for Windows. And now, once again, we have a few subdirectories.
We are installing R for the first time, so I'm going to click
here, and once again, we need to click a link to the installation file, download R 4.5.1.
Okay, so it's going to take some time, so let me pause the video for now.
Alright, so our file is downloaded, so let us go to
the downloaded files in the directory with downloads.
And now, let us click on this downloaded file, the installation file.
Alright, so we are asked if we should proceed. Yes, we'd like to proceed.
We select a language, so for us, it would be English.
And we need to go through the agreement, the installation agreement
and the license, so, let us scroll down through it.
I strongly recommend you to read it at least once.
Now, we need to select, the destination location, I suggest that we select the default one.
Similarly for the components, we are supposed to install the default ones.
Similarly, for the startup options. Similarly, I suggest that we select the default ones, and we click next.
And then for the name, here, I clicked too fast.
We would like to have it named R. And then, similarly for additional tasks.
I suggest we just select the default option. Okay, let us click Next.
Okay, and the software is being installed
right now. So, it shouldn't take that much
time we are almost there. Okay, it's finished, so let us click Finish.
And then let us go to our apps and click R.
Okay, so here we have our R installed on our machine. So, as you can see,
R is working already, but it is not the most user-friendly environment to work with, we have this
red cursor over here. There is nothing around, also even the font is not very welcoming.
So, maybe we should try to look for something which would be more user-friendly in terms of the interaction with the software.
And for that, we need RStudio. So let us close R.
And, would we like to save, this workspace image? We click no.
And once again, let us go to the browser of our choice, and this time, let us type RStudio.
Once again, one of the few first options you should see is this RStudio desktop. Let us click on this one.
And here, if we scroll down, we have two options. So first is install R, and the second is Install RStudio.
So, we have just installed R, so we are good with, with that first option.
But now, the website automatically detected that I'm on Windows machine, so I'm going to download RStudio Desktop for Windows, but of course, if you are on Macs, then
you would have an option to download it for Mac.
Okay, I'm going to click on that. And once again, it's going to take some time, so let me pause the video for now.
Alright, the file is downloaded. So, let us now click on the installation file here.
Once again, we are asked if we should proceed. We click yes.
Now we click just next. And we install it under the default directory.
So we click Install, and once again, it's going to take some time, so let me pause the video for now.
All right, we are back, basically the RStudio is installed, we just need to click on Finish.
And then we can go to our apps, click search for R, and now we can see that we have
R 4.5.1, and then we have RStudio, we click on RStudio.
And now, you can see that it looks completely different.
We have a console window, we have, this window with different options
starting from files to presentation, and then we have this environment.
We are going to stop here. We are going to come back to this particular. Thank you!